

Robert Nock

Subject Matter Expert - Submarine Cable Engineering

Manager and technical lead for submarine cable system planning, survey & installation. Wide range of international experience and highly experienced in contractor and client management.

Successful project management, for cable owners, installers and survey companies, coupled with a thorough technical knowledge and years of field experience provides a basis for sound judgement.

EDUCATION

| 1998 | Master of Science (M.Sc.) Geographic Information Systems & Civil Engineering |
|------|--|
| 1995 | Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) Hydrography |

RECENT EXPERIENCE

| 2016 | North Shore Subsea Solutions - Survey Manager for a Trans-Pacific Fiber-Optic Cable (FOC) system (USA/Hawaii/US Samoa/NZ/Australia) Management of desk top study, site visits & permit liaison, route survey operations, route design and engineering (Makaiplan) - TE Subcom |
|---------|--|
| 2016 | North Shore Subsea Solutions -Client Representative and route engineer for a submarine FOC inshore route survey (Spain) - TE Subcom |
| 2015/16 | North Shore Subsea Solutions - Project manager for a 6.5 km PLSE installation for FOC in an oilfield (Venezuela) Burial by jet sled and PLIB by diver hand jetting plus sand bag emplacement. Tasks included: contractor selection including vessels, contractor & client management, scopes and plans of work, site visits, QHSE lead and billing/payments. – Cardon4 |
| 2015 | North Shore Subsea Solutions - Project Manager for a Horizontal Directional Drilling (HDD) in Alaska for a Fiber-Optic Cable (FOC) installation program – Alcatel Lucent |



| 2015 | North Shore Subsea Solutions - Feasibility study & drilling contractor selection for 2 x FOC river crossings in North West Territories (Canada) – Ledcor Technical Services | |
|-------------|---|--|
| 2015 | North Shore Subsea Solutions - Submarine FOC burial assessment (data interpretation, analysis and reporting) – TE Subcom | |
| 2015 | North Shore Subsea Solutions - Proposal management for multi-discipline marine construction work package in Fort McMurray, Vancouver, BC - Vancouver Pile & Dredge | |
| 2014 | North Shore Subsea Solutions - Client Representative and route engineer on a Trans- Atlantic submarine FOC route survey (Canada) - TE Subcom | |
| 2014 – 2012 | Director of Projects, IT International Telecom, Montreal, Canada Submarine fiber-optic, power & seismic cable installation (Caribbean, Canada, Australia, US Samoa, Brazil). All aspects of project assessment, bid support, budget management, | |
| | departmental and client interface plus departmental lead. Survey and technical expertise | |
| 2011 – 2007 | Director, SWS (UK) Ltd, Principal owner, Technical consultancy & personnel agency Clients: Shell, BP, Maersk, Alcatel, TE Subcom, FARICE, Woodside, UVIC, Dong Energy, Huawei, MainOne | |
| 2007 – 2002 | Independent Consultant, offshore survey and installation, QC and management | |
| | Shell Oil (Sakhalin & Brunei), BP (Trinidad and Azerbaijan), Dolphin Energy (Qatar), & Alcatel (Worldwide) | |
| 2000 – 2002 | Manager, Submarine Cable Engineering, 360networks, Vancouver, BC, Canada Contractor selection & management, management of desk top study, site visits & permit liaison, route survey operations, route design and engineering for a Trans-Pacific fiber-optic cable system (USA/Canada/Hawaii/Japan) | |
| 1997 – 2000 | Senior Marine Engineer, Alcatel Submarine Networks, London, UK Route design and installation management and planning for fiber-optic submarine cable systems. Contractor & client liaison & on-site management of global operations including: route surveys, pre-laid shore end installation (PLSE), deep water installation, shallow water installation, pre-lay grapnel runs (PLGR) and post-lay burial (PLIB) | |
| 1995 – 1997 | Hydrographic Surveyor, Racal Survey, USA & Trinidad | |
| 1991 – 1992 | Marine Navigation QC, Western Geophysical | |



1986 – 1991 Hydrographic Surveyor, Royal Navy

| SPECIALIZATION SUMMARY | | | |
|------------------------------|--|--------------------------------------|---|
| Submarine Cable Installation | Submarine Cable Route Design & Engineering | Hydrographic & Geophysical Surveying | Post-lay inspection and burial |
| Risk Assessment | Contract Management | Offshore Client Representation | Sub-contractor selection and management |
| Permit Management | Feasibility Studies & Site visits | Project management | Quality & HSSE |

| MARINE SAFETY & MEDICAL COURSES | |
|--|--|
| Further Offshore & Emergency Training valid to 4 May 2018 | OPITO course – Falck Safety Services, Houston, USA |
| Marine Medical Certificate (ENG1 equivalent) valid to March 2018 | Mariners Clinic, Vancouver, BC, Canada |

| TRAINING | | |
|-------------|---|--------------------------------|
| 2011 | Project Management | Open University (UK) |
| 2006 | Offshore Risk Assessment | Instinct Training (UK) |
| 2004 | Cable Ship Navigation | Global Marine Systems Ltd (UK) |
| 1999 & 2004 | Makai Plan GIS cable engineering software | Alcatel (UK) |

| DETAILS | |
|-----------------------|------------------------|
| Nationality – British | Age – 49 |
| Residency – Canadian | Seaman Book - Canadian |